MOHAMED OMAR FAROOK

Email: mohamedomarfarookvm@gmail.com

Mobile: +65 96567792



CAREER OBJECTIVE

Innovative, creative and a proven team player with 5 years of experience in designing, developing and managing complex web and mobile applications and programs for various clients. I hope to share my skills, expertise and experience with your team and valuable clients.

STRENGTH

- Proficient in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, LESS, SASS, Bootstrap
- Experience in using Front End Frameworks Angular, Angular Material, React, React Native, VueJS, Redux, Nextjs
- Keen understanding of responsive design principles.
- Proficient knowledge in AWS Cloud services.
- Experienced in using Functional, Unit testing methods and Code Review to deliver high quality, fit for purpose software with emphasis on testability and maintainability.
- Strong experience of working in agile teams and using Continuous Delivery to get quick feedback and improve constantly
- Possess a knack of team work and comfortable working cross functional

WORK EXPERIENCE

Company : Apar Technologies Pte Ltd

Designation : Senior Developer

Duration : Nov 2020 - Present

Company : Aspire Digital Technologies

Designation: Technical Lead

Duration : MAR 2020 – Oct 2020

Company : TATA Consultancy Services Private Limited

Designation : IT Analyst

Duration : AUG 2015 – MAR 2020

PROJECTS:

Client: Development Bank Of Singapore – Singapore (Senior Developer – Nov 2020 – Present)

- Widget framework development based on micro-front end, that can ensure the end-to end reusability of product based Angular components across the DBS IBG platforms.
- Driving the team of UI developers for developing the widgets based on Angular 8.
- Segregating the widgets based on the platform and collaborating with the product leads to ensure the re-usability of widgets across multiple products.
- Handling the complexities and leading the efficient design of a single widget that can consume different sources and be the single source of truth to the end user.
- Established appropriate review procedures to ensure consistent and high quality deliverables.

Technologies:

HTML5, CSS3, Typescript, Angular 8, SCSS, Node.js, Webpack, Angular CLI

Client: Obeikan – Saudi Arabia (Front End Tech Lead – Mar 2020 – Oct 2020)

- The paramount objective is to develop Business-to-Business E-Commerce application for Manufacturing Company.
- Integrated layout architecture from SAP Commerce CMS in angular framework for home and static pages.
- Implemented SSR and State Transfer in our application to support SEO and to improve the performance of the application.
- Lead the team and working closely with the design team and project managers and ensured projects are delivered in a timely manner.
- Interpreted and executed designs correctly as requested by client.

Technologies:

Angular 8, Angular Material, Bootstrap 4, SASS, HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, jQuery

Client: MYER - Australia (Lead Front End Develop - Aug 2018 – Mar 2020)

- The imperative part is to deal with the development of Online e-commerce web application and iOS native in-store application (used for warehouse fulfilment). Communicated directly with their Senior Management during the sourcing process
- Designs, develops and relaunches responsive e-commerce sites of the client
- Improved Site Performance by implementing asynchronous content rendering (CMS) by using custom reusable components in Reactjs.
- Executes full-stack website launches specializing in front-end features, browser manipulation, and cross-browser compatibility
- Managed multiple projects with a team of backend engineers and QA from planning to website launch.

Oversees creation and maintenance of front-end standard documents

Technologies:

ReactJs, React Native, NextJs, Redux, EmotionJs, AWS, Jenkins.

Client: BJ's – USA (Front End Developer - July 2017 – July 2018)

- The paramount objective is to develop an application for both Business-to Consumer and Business-to-Business as a part of single project.
- Integrated layout architecture in angular framework for home and PDP page.
- Implemented SSR and State Transfer in our application to support SEO and to improve the performance of the application.
- Integrated third party libraries like Certona, Criteo in our application for Recommended products.
- Interpreted and executed designs correctly as requested by client.

Technologies:

Angular 5, Bootstrap 4, SASS, HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, jQuery

Client: DSG -USA

(Front End Developer - Nov 2015 – Jun 2017)

- The prime scope is to build a comprehensive responsive frontend part of e-commerce application which includes adding pertinent promotions, shopping path, purchase path, Buy online and pick up in store (BOPIS) feature.
- Coordinated with team of UX designers to create new Web Content Management system.
- Actively participates and engages the Software Support team in resolving production issues
- Converted Photoshop layouts to web pages using HTML, CSS, Flex and bootstrap
- Worked closely with the design team and project managers and ensured projects are delivered in a timely manner

Technologies:

Angular JS (version 1.4), Bootstrap 3, SASS, LESS, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript

CERTIFICATIONS

AWS Certified Developer Associate. (Valid from 4 Aug 2021 to 4 Aug 2024)

EDUCATION

B. E (Computer Science and Engineering)
Anna University, Chennai, Tamil Nadu Aug 11– Aug 15